THE 9TH PROFESSIONAL
FUNERAL TECHNIQUE COMPETITION
JUDGE
An embalmer
pours their emotions into their craft
and preserves culture with customs.
They help the dead rest in peace
and bring comfort to the living.
Silently,
they pass on the value of life.
AUDITORIUM, CIVIL AFFAIRS
VOCATIONAL AND TECHNICAL COLLEGE
Every life arrives in this world
with its own cries.
They are cleaned gently
by their parents or nurses,
completing the baptism to welcome a life.
So when a life
bids farewell to this world
amidst the cries of others,
they should be given
a baptism of farewell.
JUDGE
ADAPTED FROM THE ORIGINAL WORK
"LOVER" BY SHE MU SI
SHANGHAI YAKANG HOSPITAL
-Your earrings are very pretty.
-Okay, it's yours.
-How about the e-mail to Lisa?
-Don't worry, I've sent it. Be good.
Ma, what are you eating?
Why did I even give you the enzymes?
Director Liu,
are you back from training?
Thank you for your hard work.
-Can you please stop?
-Zhuang Jie?
It's minor surgery. Minimally invasive.
Qin!
You will meet Colin next week.
Show him the Equipment Dept.
Don't ignore my calls again.
After today, I won't have my gallbladder.
Please do it for me!
Why are you still acting
like a tough gangster?
It's not easy to get hospitalized.
Which medical salesperson
doesn't want to enter Yakang?
My illness is a blessing in disguise.
You're almost the top player
in the wellness industry.
Aren't you satisfied yet?
Stop flattering me.
Are you jealous of me
since you're my competitor
for top sales every year?
Okay, you are good.
When you're in the operating room,
just keep blabbering.
You're right. I heard that my surgeon
is the hospital's vice president.
Let me think.
How can I leave a good impression later?
Great.
Just lie down.
Overall, there is no problem
with the operational process just now.
Just be aware
of your body position and gait.
When standing,
your two feet should be
in a T-shape or a figure-eight shape
to move forward and backward freely
and turn to the side swiftly.
Before bathing,
check every area of the skin carefully.
Some tiny wounds
need to be cleared, disinfected,
and closed in advance.
In addition,
don't rush through washing their hair.
From the sideburns to the Baihui acupoint.
From the Shenting to the Baihui acupoint.
From the Wangu to the Baihui acupoint.
Repeat several times.
Sink in your chest and hunch your back.
Do not stick out your chest and belly.
This will help you
to control your strength
and allow you to work longer.
After death,
one's pores will become loose
and hair will fall out more easily.
So be careful of how much force you exert.
Some family members will choose
to watch the ceremony on-site.
So every move you make
will affect their feelings.
Everyone,
facing death is never a simple thing.
A long time ago,
our work was considered dirty,
vile, and despicable.
Even today,
no one would be willing
to stay too long at where we work.
After saying, "Thank you,"
no one would say, "See you again."
However, I hope you understand
that we are not the ones they hate
but death.
NEXT STATION, NANPING NORTH
Excuse me. Thank you.
Thanks.
Are you from Nanping?
Is something the matter?
Don't you remember me?
We know each other.
Excuse me.
Was that necessary?
We really do know each other.
Chen Maidong.
You really are a piece of work.
I am Zhuang Jie.
We were high school classmates.
Have I changed that much?
Yes.
Okay, I'll take it as a compliment.
You've changed a lot too.
I was only sure that it was you
after seeing the scar on your forehead.
Sorry,
I don't recall your special features.
Me? Do I not have any?
Sorry.
I really didn't recognize you.
I have something to do. I'm leaving.
Did you think I was hitting you up?
Yes.
So is this how you would respond
to a girl hitting you up?
Yes.
Are you driving? Give me a ride.
Yes,
but I'm busy.
Take a taxi.
Whatever.
ALL WILL BE WELL
WHEN PEOPLE AND FAMILY ARE IN HARMONY
Come on.
Mr. He!
You're back, Jie.
Why didn't you tell us
that you were coming?
I could've picked you up. Allow me.
-It's okay. Taxis are convenient.
-Let me.
I'll get you some food.
No, let's have dinner together tonight.
I'm going to surprise my mom later.
Okay.
Come.
Gosh!
Why has the house become like this?
I'm burning the midnight oil every night
with He Niaoniao.
Her grades are terrible.
I can't bear to look at it.
Has my mom
improved her braised chicken recipe?
What's this?
There is a kite competition
in the town this autumn.
I'm trying to improve
my kite-making skills.
How does it look?
You just like to keep yourself busy.
It must be hard on you
to go to bed early and get up early.
It's not hard on me.
Your mom has it worse.
Let me tell you.
Last night,
your mom was almost
about to crack open He Niaoniao's skull.
She said she wanted to see her brains
and how they are different
from yours and Zhuang Yan's.
Well, isn't having me
as her dad the only difference
that He Niaoniao has
from you and your brother?
-Since I was a kid, my grades have been--
-Mr. He.
Stop making excuses for He Niaoniao.
Her mind is sharp.
She's just using it on the wrong things.
Let me deal with her.
FUNERAL VEHICLE
Master!
You are finally back.
Something always happens when you're away.
-What's wrong?
-Hurry inside and take a look.
This way.
GOOD BEGINNING AND GOOD ENDING,
WITH THE UTMOST TRUTH AND SINCERITY
Who has hidden my buddy?
The deceased passed away
while they were drinking.
All your brothers are here,
yet you left by yourself!
-Quiet down!
-That's how the drunkards came here.
Huang, come out quickly!
Let's call the police.
Come out, Huang!
Huang!
Are you friends with Huang too?
We're ironclad brothers!
-Who are you?
-Who?
We just had a drink together.
Did you forget?
-Then I'll have a drink with you.
-Sure.
Let's go. Let's drink together.
Brothers!
There's more liquor, guys.
Let's go!
There is liquor.
-There's liquor.
-Come. Come here to drink.
I'm going to buy you drinks.
-I'll buy you drinks. Wait for a moment.
-Okay, go and buy drinks.
-Is that everyone?
-Yes.
Five men are as strong as fifty men.
Stop yapping. Stay here.
Proceed with cremation.
Let them out when they sober up.
Seriously, these guys.
There's a time and place for drinking.
They're troublemakers.
Feng Xilun, I said to stop yapping.
Come over here.
Where's the liquor?
Ever heard of the Battle of Antietam?
No.
It had the highest daily casualties
among the American civil wars.
Before clearing the battlefield,
the regiment commander
specifically requested his superiors
to allow the soldiers to drink liquor
before burying the bodies
of their companions.
For some people,
they need alcohol to numb them
in order to complete some special tasks.
Even drunkards have the right to be sad.
If we called the police,
they would sober up
in the detention center.
In the future,
whenever they miss their friend,
they would be reminded
of their poor behavior.
That would double their pain.
I understand, Master.
I was wrong.
Pour them some tea. Look after them.
Okay. When they sober up,
I will take them to send off their friend.
Something funny is happening
at the town committee today.
Indeed. How did Wu Xuehua
meet such an opponent?
Yes, they were hard to deal with.
Madam Wu?
Madam Wu,
you have been beaten so many times.
-Excuse me.
-Why can't you return a single ball?
That's right.
They really have her beat.
The opponent obviously came prepared.
Even if you were to go,
you would be beaten.
I really don't believe it.
Hurry up.
I'm coming.
Come.
SCIENTIFIC FITNESS FOR THE SAKE
OF OUR NATION'S WONDERFUL LIFE
Come here.
Come again.
Come on!
Mr. Wang, your turn.
-Come on.
-You've got this.
Play well, Mr. Wang.
Wipe your sweat.
Good luck!
That's enough. We're playing ping pong.
Why are you making it sound
like we're boxing?
Come. You two, come at me together.
-Bring it on.
-Go, all the best.
-Come on, good luck.
-Go!
-Fight well, come on.
-Come on.
-You must win. Go.
Come on!
Another miss.
Why didn't you receive it?
-Awesome.
-Incredible.
Madam Wu, let's keep going.
Mrs. Chen,
I know you are a professional.
You shouldn't bully us like this.
Are you not advocating
for national fitness?
Well, I am the director
of the local Women's Federation.
Well, I can't be playing
ping pong here all day.
From my observations,
you are horsing around every day.
That's why I am training you.
Madam Wu, what activity are you hosting?
Jie? When did you come back?
I didn't hear it from your mom.
I had the impulse
to come back for a vacation.
It's good to see you back.
Stay longer this time.
Let me tell you.
Our town is now changing every day.
You won't get bored anytime soon,
all right?
Where are you going?
The match isn't over yet.
Come.
Help me. I beg you.
I can't.
You can. Come on.
Ready, go!
-Great.
-This…
This is…
Is there no one else
on the town committee?
You try to fool me with some amateurs.
Mark my words.
If you don't solve
my grandson's marriage problem,
no one can leave today.
My grandson
is a great person
and a pillar of the country.
He is the most indispensable talent
in our town.
If even he can't find a partner,
what's the use of your department?
Madam Wu,
is this grandma trying
to find a wife for her grandson?
Yes, she comes often.
She has almost driven me crazy.
Madam Wu, let me see
if I can help you.
Good girl.
Ma'am,
I am a layman when it comes to ping pong,
but I am good at finding a partner.
Girl,
if you are a spy sent by Wu Xuehua,
I won't spare you.
Ma'am,
is there no more trust between people?
Do I look like a traitor?
All right, then tell me.
What's your plan?
These days, arranged marriages
by parents or matchmakers
are no longer popular.
The best place to find a partner
is at a gathering with friends
while eating and drinking.
You don't say!
My grandson isn't into that.
What about dating websites?
Social media?
That's even more unreliable.
We don't even know
who is on the other side yet,
and they want to collect my money.
You don't want to spend money either.
Ma'am,
have you heard of WeChat's Shake?
Low cost, high opportunities.
It's practically tailored
for your grandson.
Look.
DISCOVER, SHAKE
SHAKE
How do you shake this?
Let me teach you.
SHAKE
SEARCHING FOR PEOPLE NEARBY
XIAOLEI, 25KM AWAY
Will a girl appear after shaking it?
There will definitely be girls.
You have to tirelessly
shake, search, and chat.
Not bad, girl.
Although you have poor coordination,
you have a sharp brain.
Ma'am, as long as you
continue shaking diligently,
I promise you'll get
a granddaughter-in-law this year.
Teach me again.
Look.
Look for this page.
Swipe to open and click into it.
Hear the noise.
RA?NI, 24KM AWAY
Let me tell you again.
Look for this page.
Click this.
After that, listen.
LIAOGEN BRAISED CHICKEN
Thank you.
What would you like?
-One chicken.
-Two drumsticks.
-Okay.
-Yes.
-Here you go.
-Thanks.
-What would you like?
-A drumstick and a wing.
A drumstick and a wing.
Okay. Thank you.
Okay. Hi, what would you like?
I never eat chicken.
Don't you sell anything else?
You!
What are you doing here?
Where did you come from?
-Ma'am.
-You…
I want a chicken and a drumstick.
Okay.
It's not the holidays.
What made you come home suddenly?
Were you fired?
Can't you wish for something good for me?
I had a dream.
I dreamed that you missed me.
I took my annual leave
to stay with you for a few days.
As always, you are a sweet talker.
Do you think I believe you?
Mom, don't you miss me?
Shoo!
Don't disgust me here.
When would I have time to miss you?
We're closing the stall early today.
I'll give you two drumsticks for free.
It's a new flavor.
Tell the folks about it.
Grandma.
-Thank you.
-Okay.
I just passed by the town committee.
I helped Madam Wu deal with a grandma
who was looking for a date
for her grandson.
I'm drained after talking my mouth off.
Madam Wu really has a hard time
being the Women's Federation's director.
Where do I put this?
Let me do it.
Let's hurry home. I'm hungry.
EGG FLAVORED NOODLES
Zhangyue, that's enough.
There are so many dishes already.
This is the last one.
Here it comes.
Your favorite shredded sweet potato.
Mr. He, your cooking has improved.
This is nothing.
We would need your mom to make a feast.
What time does Niaoniao get out of school?
The time she gets out of school
depends on how much detention she gets.
It seems like you just can't stop
dissing your daughter.
I diss her every day,
but she still doesn't care at all.
If I followed your method
of motivational education,
she would drive me mad.
She's back.
You brat! Can't you be more careful?
Do you want to break the door?
-That's enough.
-I'm starving!
Unbelievable.
Jie!
Let me take a look at you.
You do look much fairer.
The whitening mask works well, right?
Yes.
Why does she care about whitening?
She is still young.
You are both mental.
Niaoniao, quick, come over and eat.
You scold me as soon as I come in.
Do you see this?
I'm not allowed to speak in this house.
He Niaoniao, don't accuse me.
Jie, take me to Shanghai quickly.
Even if you go to Shanghai,
you won't even be able
to read the hotel signs.
Jie, look. She's always humiliating me.
True, the way our mom talks
is quite problematic.
Stop talking about me.
I haven't asked you yet.
Why did you suddenly take leave?
Is the company doing badly?
Remember this.
Our company is among the top ten
medical device companies globally.
Your daughter
is a senior technical sales rep.
I can enjoy paid time off.
So what if it's in the top ten
or top five?
You don't own the company.
You should pay more attention
to our family business.
Didn't I applaud you every time
you broke your sales record?
Stop doing that nonsense.
Listen, Mr. He and I
plan to expand our business.
No more slaughtering chickens at home.
The blood smells bad
and it's not environmentally friendly.
Coincidentally,
you're back now.
Starting tomorrow,
you will do the deliveries.
This way, Mr. He will have time
to look for a factory with me.
I'm here on vacation.
Spoiled brat.
Zhuang Jie, let me tell you,
I don't care if you are called
Ashley or Jessica in Shanghai.
When you're back home,
you are my worker.
She's right.
This shredded sweet potato
is stuck in my teeth.
Mom, just talk less.
CLASSICAL MUSIC ARCHIVES
POSSESSION ORGANIZER
It's time for breakfast.
Dad, I told you I don't like
the breakfast from this place.
Can you show me some respect?
I'll buy it from another store next time.
I didn't buy this for you today.
Fine, for my sister's sake.
By the way, Dad,
don't leave in a hurry yet.
About the sneakers…
If you need money,
discuss it with your mom.
Zhuang Jie.
Zhuang Jie, don't laze around in bed.
Tutor He Niaoniao on her homework later.
Did you hear that?
I haven't dared to reply
to her class's WeChat group.
Also, don't forget
to do the deliveries this afternoon.
Clean up your messy hair and dirty face
before going out.
Don't affect
Liaogen Chicken's brand image.
You're the same every day,
always sleeping in.
Mom.
I'm busy now. We can talk tonight.
Mom!
He Niaoniao, are you a monkey on a stick?
Jie, I'm firmly on your side.
Don't make an enemy out of me.
Niaoniao, do you want
to make some extra cash?
-Gentler.
-You don't have much hair.
Why hire someone to wash it?
We city people are like this.
By the way, Jie,
I forgot to mention
that 30 is the price
for washing your hair.
Scalp massage is 50.
Shampoo and massage, 50 in total.
Sixty.
Deal, but it has to be
at least 15 minutes.
Deal.
Niaoniao,
during my vacation here,
I'll let you wash my hair.
Why don't you take the money
and sign up for a cram school?
I'll think about it.
My schedule is quite full too.
I was planning
to watch a concert with the money.
He Niaoniao, be serious.
I've been there.
You obviously changed the score
on your math paper.
Mom might miss it, but you can't fool me.
I won't tell her this,
but you have to go to cram school
whether you want to or not.
Jie, I forgot to mention it just now.
The second basin of water is half-price.
It's 30 yuan.
What?
Do you want it?
It's okay if you don't.
Come back.
You profiteer.
That's who I am.
I accept WeChat Pay but no late payments.
Transfer it yourself.
Don't transfer extra.
Jie, just enjoy your vacation.
Why are you Shaking?
Who did I Shake?
Here, someone is Shaking you here.
They're called Old Cedar.
She looks like a grandma.
OLD CEDAR
Sure, add her.
Jie, you have to give me
another 100 yuan as hush money.
He Niaoniao,
are you not ashamed of yourself?
If you don't pay up, I'll tell our mom
that you've been Shaking
like an indecent girl.
He Niaoniao, give me my phone.
No.
He Niaoniao,
you aren't done washing my hair yet!
Be self-reliant, Jie.
-He Niaoniao!
-Hurry up on the deliveries.
Or else, Mom will scold you.
LIAOGEN BRAISED CHICKEN,
LIAOGEN SPECIAL FOOD
TONGJIN GUANYIN PALACE OF SHUIMEN,
QUANJUN
Don't mention 300,000.
Even if it's three million,
who will have the guts to stop me?
You!
You're finally here.
We're having a gratitude dinner.
We can't run out of food.
Gratitude for what? It's quite lively.
My dad's funeral was a few days ago.
A lot of people were there to help.
Sorry, I had no idea.
Let me give you a discount.
No need.
He was 97. It was a joyful mourning.
Congratulations then.
I mean, you're blessed.
I'll leave you to it. I'm leaving first.
Why don't you grab a bite too?
-No, thanks.
-Watch some opera then.
The Han emperor Liu Bang…
Think of it as a show of support.
This is my gratitude dinner.
Come on, sit here.
I specially invited this troupe
from the provincial capital.
They're performing Farewell My Concubine.
Keep watching. I need to get back to it.
Just an ordinary man,
yet you are someone
who makes a woman
fall in love.
In this world
full of desire and chaos,
how could there be
such a sincere, straightforward,
and deeply sentimental man like you?
From that time on,
you have been engraved
in my heart.
-Great!
-Excellent!
Full of nonsense!
Tell me. Is it Liu Bang?
Did he send you to convince me?
I was merely listening
to the call of my heart.
That Liu Bang
is a scoundrel, a gangster.
He dimmed the romantic night
and disregarded the yin and yang
between men and women.
Listen to the four corners
The song of Chu
Tearing my heart apart
Chen Maidong.
What a coincidence.
Not really.
I'm just here to have a meal.
You aren't eating anything.
Aren't you just watching
the love triangle?
Well,
you're sitting in my grandma's seat.
Is it necessary
to raise my seniority
just to drive me away?
What is it, girl?
Do you want to be a grandma?
It's you.
The Shake girl.
Is this your grandson?
ALL ANIMALS IN THIS PROGRAM
WERE TREATED KINDLY